ffn.com 2016-10-17

# FriendFinder Networks Inc. | A leading Internet-based social networking company.

This Privacy Policy (the " _Policy_ ") applies to all websites (the " _FFN Website(s)_ ") FriendFinder Networks Inc. and its subsidiaries (collectively, " _FFN_ ", " _us_ ", " _we_ ").

We understand that the privacy of its members, subscribers, guests and/or visitors (collectively, " _Members_ ", " _you_ " or " _your_ ") is very important. We developed this Policy to ensure that your privacy is protected while using any of the FFN Websites or services.

1\. A Special Note About Children.

Children under eighteen years of age are prohibited from using the FFN Websites or services. We ask that children not submit information to us.

2\. How We Collect, Use and Disclose Information

What Information Do We Collect?

During the registration process for, or while using, any of the FFN Websites, you may choose to provide us with certain "Personal Information" including:

  * your name and email address,
  * billing information,
  * "Sensitive Personal Information", which includes your racial or ethnic origins, political or religious beliefs, or sexuality.

When we refer to "Personal Information" in this Policy, unless we say otherwise, this includes "Sensitive Personal Information."

We may also collect information about your activities or postings on FFN Website when you choose to send us personal correspondence such as emails or letters or when other FFN Website users or third parties send us correspondence, which may include their comments about you. All this information will be kept in a file that is accessed only by authorized FFN personnel or representatives.

On some of the FFN Websites, you may choose to use our referral service to tell a friend or friends about us. In this case, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address and email your friend an invite to him or her to visit an FFN Website.

Providing your Personal Information to us is voluntary. However, if you do not provide your Personal Information to us, you will not be able to access some or all of our services.

How do We Use Your Information?

When you provide Personal Information to us, we will use it to contact you about our services, to process payment for our services, and to tailor our services to your meet your preferences.

We use your Personal Information for many specific purposes, including:

  * emailing you with news and updates about the FFN Websites
  * improving and customizing our content and product offerings
  * analyzing FFN Website usage and delivering information (such as banners and promotions) targeted to your interests
  * providing you with information about the products and services provided by the FFN Websites or third parties

If you have provided us with certain Personal Information, we will also use it to facilitate your communication with other members, for example, by the use of the message center or delivery of "Cupid Reports" or "Ice Breakers". 

We may also use your Personal Information to resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, enforce any agreements, policies and rules governing the use of FFN Websites, and observe the FFN Websites for quality control and customer service purposes. 

If you use our referral services, we will use your friend's name and email address only to send an invitation and to track the status of the referral. Your friend(s) may use the unsubscribe function in the email or contact us at privacy@friendfindernetworks.com to request that we remove their email address from our records. 

When and to Whom Will We Disclose Your Information?

Due to the nature of many of the services provided by the FFN Websites, certain of your Personal Information will be disclosed to other Members. As an example, if you complete a "dating" profile and choose to disclose your religious affiliation or ethnic origin, this information will be available to other Members using the services on the applicable FFN Website. By providing this type of profile information to us, you have consented to the use and disclosure of your Personal Information in this manner.

We may share or transfer your Personal Information with our subsidiaries operating other FFN Websites so that they can send you information about their products or services that you may be interested in. 

We also disclose Personal Information to our service providers (for example, credit card processing companies, billing services) as reasonably necessary or appropriate to provide services on the FFN Websites. Our service providers are legally required by us to protect your Personal Information. Because many of the FFN Websites operate or use service providers located in different countries, your Personal Information may be transferred to a country in which you do not reside, and while in that foreign country, may be accessible to its law enforcement authorities. 

We may be required to disclose your Personal Information in order to comply with a court order, subpoena, search warrant, or as otherwise compelled by law. In addition, we expressly reserve the right to disclose your Personal Information when we have a good faith belief that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, to enforce our agreements, policies, and rules governing your use of the FFN Websites, to cooperate with law enforcement, and/or to report information concerning a threat of serious injury or death.

We DO NOT sell or rent any of your Personal Information to third parties for marketing purposes without your express permission or consent. We may, however, disclose to third-party advertisers certain aggregated or hashed (i.e., encrypted) information in a manner that no longer reflects or references an individually identifiable user, for other marketing and promotional purposes. 

When you provide your Personal Information and Sensitive Personal Information to us, you consent to our use and disclosure of that information as described in this Policy. If you do not want us to use or disclose your Personal Information as described in this Policy, do not provide it to us. We note that this may result in you being unable to access some or all of our services. 

3\. Our Use of Cookies and Your Options; Pixel Tags; Do-Not Track

FFN Websites use "cookies" to store and sometimes track information to make your online experience easier and more personalized. 

Cookies are small pieces of data that are stored by a user's web browser on the user's storage drive. Cookies may record information that is accessed by a user on a webpage in order to simplify subsequent interactions with that website by the same user, or to streamline the user's transactions on related webpages. Cookies make it easier for a user to move from webpage to webpage and to complete transactions over the Internet. 

Most major web browsers are set up so that they will initially accept cookies, but you may modify your computer's preferences to issue you an alert when a cookie is downloaded, or to disable the ability of third parties to download a cookie to you. If you choose to reject all cookies, there are areas of FFN Websites that may not function properly. You may obtain further information about cookies and how they function at: [http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie](http://friendfinder.com/p/offsite.cgi?http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie).

We, or a data provider or advertiser that we have engaged, may also place or recognize a cookie on your browser to enable you to receive customized ads or content. These cookies contain no Personal Information. The cookies may reflect de-identified demographic or other data that is linked to data that you have voluntarily have submitted to us (e.g., your email address) that we may share with the data provider or advertiser solely in a hashed (i.e., non-human readable) format. To opt-out of these cookies or to learn more about them, please go to [http://www.aboutads.info/choices](http://friendfinder.com/p/offsite.cgi?http://www.aboutads.info/choices).

We may also use standard Internet technology, such as web beacons or 1x1 "gifs" and other similar technologies (collectively "Pixel Tags"). A Pixel Tag is an electronic image, often a single pixel (1x1), that is ordinarily not visible to Members and may be associated with cookies on the Members' storage drives. We use Pixel Tags to track your use of the FFN Websites, for advertising, marketing, or promotional purposes, and to determine whether you opened an email message from us. The information also enables us to customize the services we offer. 

Other parties may collect Personal Information about your online activities over time and across different websites when you use FFN Services. We honor web browser "do not track" signals that provide you with the ability to exercise choice regarding the collection of Personal Information about your online activities over time and across third-party websites or online services, when the web browser's http header includes the field "dnt:1". We do not presently honor any other types of "Do Not Track" mechanism.

4\. Collection, Use and Disclosure of Personal Information by Third Parties

This Policy only addresses the use and disclosure of Personal Information that we collect from you. To the extent that you disclose your Personal Information to others while using the FFN Websites or other websites throughout the internet, different rules may apply to its use, maintenance, or disclosure. FFN does not control the privacy policies of third parties, and you are subject to the privacy policies or practices of those third parties.

5\. Your Use of FFN Websites' Members' Information

You may not use another FFN Websites' Members' information, whether private or not, for commercial purposes, to spam, to harass, or to make unlawful threats. We reserve the right to terminate those who misuse other Members' information or who otherwise violate any user agreements, policies, or rules governing the use of any FFN Website.

6\. Do Not Disclose Your Personal Information or Password.

Please DO NOT post, share or disclose in public forums (e.g., chat rooms, blogs) any Personal Information that you do not wish other Members to know. We encourage you to ask questions before you disclose your Personal Information to others. Similarly, you should never disclose or share your password with anyone else. If you lose control of your password, you may lose substantial control over your Personal Information and may be subject to legally binding actions taken on your behalf. If your password has been compromised for any reason, you should immediately change your password and/or contact us at: [privacy@friendfindernetworks.com](mailto:privacy@friendfindernetworks.com).

7\. How We Protect Your Information

FFN Websites use reasonable security measures to help protect and prevent the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. We use industry standard efforts, such as firewalls, to safeguard your Personal Information. While "perfect security" does not exist on the Internet, or elsewhere, our technical staff works hard to help ensure your secure use of our services. 

8\. Where we are Located

FFN is located in the United States. If you are visiting any of the FFN Websites from outside the United States, you must be aware that your Personal Information may be transferred to, stored, and processed in the United States or other countries in which FFN or its service providers are located. The data protection and other laws of the United States and these other countries might not be as comprehensive as those in your country, and your Personal Information may be accessible to law enforcement authorities in the United States or of other countries.

When you use the FFN Websites, you consent to us transferring your Personal Information (which includes, for the avoidance of doubt, your Sensitive Personal Information) from your country to the United States or countries in which the FFN or its service providers are located for the purposes described in this Policy.

9\. Reviewing, Updating, Accessing or Removing Your Personal Information and Registering Privacy-Related Complaints

Once you register, you will be able to review and change much of your Personal Information including:

> Your email address   
> Your city, state, ZIP or other postal code, country   
> Your password   
> Your profile 

Please promptly update your information by logging in to your account and following the screen prompts. We strongly urge you to change your password periodically to help reduce the risk of unauthorized access to your account information. 

You have the right to ask in writing whether we hold any Personal Information about you, and to see that information as well as how we collect, use or disclose your Personal Information. We note that we may not be able to provide you with all of the information you request, depending on the circumstances (e.g., if it contains the Personal Information of other Members). There may be a charge for any copy of Personal Information requested. 

Upon your request, we will remove your credit card number, credit card expiration date and other Personal Information from our main databases. We note that, despite your request, we may retain in our files certain data (including credit card information) if necessary to:

  * resolve disputes
  * troubleshoot problems
  * comply with credit card merchant banking and association agreements, rules or regulations
  * enhance security, reduce fraud, or comply with the law, or
  * enforce any agreements, policies, and rules governing your use of FFN Websites

We note that despite our best efforts to remove information from our database on your request, removed information may exist in backup copies or other users' caches. As an example, an information exchange with another Member may remain in that Member's e-mail boxes, computer caches, or instant message archive. Whether your exchanged information is kept by another Member is beyond the control of FFN. 

You will be able to update, modify and delete some of your Personal Information by logging in with your password and modifying or deleting your profile. For all other requests to access, update, modify or delete your Personal Information, please:

  * Email us at: [privacy@friendfindernetworks.com](mailto:privacy@friendfindernetworks.com), or
  * mail us at: FriendFinder Networks Inc. at 910 E. Hamilton Ave, Sixth Floor, Campbell, CA 95008, USA, Attn: Privacy, or
  * telephone us at: (408) 702-1040.

You are entitled to contact us using the above contact information to register a privacy-related complaint. We will explain our complaint procedure to you and investigate all complaints. If a complaint is justified, we will take all appropriate steps to set the situation right. We will also let you know what other complaint procedures may be available to you. 

If you are a European or Swiss Citizen, to register a privacy-related complaint, please see the section below entitled "Safe Harbor Principles and Privacy Complaints by European and Swiss Citizens". 

10\. Safe Harbor Principles and Privacy Complaints by European and Swiss Citizens

Please note: this Section applies to European Union and Swiss residents only.

FFN complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. FFN has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view FFN's certification, please visit:

In compliance with the U.S. - European Union and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Principles, FFN commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union and Swiss citizens with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact us at: 

> FriendFinder Networks Inc.   
> 910 E. Hamilton Ave, Sixth Floor,  
>  Campbell, CA 95008, USA   
> European Union (or Swiss) Safe Harbor   
> 408) 702-1040   
> privacy@friendfindernetworks.com 

We have further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the US-EU and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed by us, please visit the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR website at: [http://www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints](http://friendfinder.com/p/offsite.cgi?http://www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints), for more information and to file a complaint. 

11\. Revisions to this Privacy Policy

We reserve our right, in our sole and absolute discretion, to revise, amend, modify or revoke this Privacy Policy at any time, and in any manner to the fullest extent permitted by law. If the changes are significant, we will provide a more prominent notice. Changes to this Policy will be effective by posting revisions on the FFN Websites.

FRIENDFINDER NETWORKS INC. PRIVACY POLICY Effective on: December 31, 2013
